Quick overview of Arduino.
So Arduino is a prerequisite for this course.
The knowledge of Arduino is prerequisite for this course.
So in this video, we are going to see a quick overview of Arduino.
So Arduino is an open source hardware, and it is a single board microcontroller.
And the best part of Arduino is we can use different modules and sensors with it, right?
So let's say your project needs some type of temperature recording, so you can use a sensor for temperature
and you can attach some sensor of temperature with Arduino board and you can achieve your goal easily,
right?
Similarly, if you want to record some type of pressure, there is a sensor for pressure as well.
But in our case, we need to do work with RFID.
So we are going to use a module for RFID.
The module is known as RC 522.
This is the module which we are going to use with Arduino board and we are going to attach this module
with Arduino board and do our goals right.
So we are going to use Arduino Uno.
There are different versions of Arduino as well.
Arduino Uno is one of the most famous version of Arduino, but there is Arduino Mega as well.
Arduino Nano, Arduino Micro Mini.
So these are different versions of Arduino boards as well, right?
So we are going to use Arduino board for few of our lectures in future and we are going to use RC 5
to 2 module with it to do the goals, right?
So this is the quick overview of Arduino.
And if you don't know about Arduino, I would suggest that you should watch few tutorials of Arduino
or just go ahead of few videos of Arduino on YouTube.
So you will get a quick overview of how Arduino board works, right?